chandlerproject.org 2012-09-20

# Chandler Wiki : Hub Privacy Policy

We run a free public service named Chandler Hub because we think it is a neat thing to do. We are not here to sell your information or push ads on you. 

Our Privacy Policy, the official copy of which is below, says how we intend to manage any information about you we happen to collect. It is intended to be very consumer friendly, while being clear about how your data might be collected and used. 

The major points of our Privacy Policy are summarized for you here, however only the actual Privacy Policy provided below is binding upon you and OSAF. 

##  Privacy Policy summary 

  1. The Privacy Policy covers OSAF, Chandler Project, Chandler Hub, and any other web site or service offered by OSAF. 
  2. The Privacy Policy is part of the [Chandler Hub Terms of Service](http://chandlerproject.org/tos). 
  3. We don't control any sites or organizations except ourselves. 
  4. We may show ads someday. 
  5. We use cookies, keep log files, and may use web beacons if we want to. We use this data to monitor and support our service. 
  6. We'll ask for your name, email address, and other simple account information. 
  7. If you share your data with friends, we need to keep track of a little extra information about who's sharing with whom. 
  8. If you send us email, we hang on to it. 
  9. Groups we work with may have different privacy policies. 
  10. We might keep track of which links you click on in our sites. 
  11. When we share data with another group, we'll require them to use our privacy policies. 
  12. We may release personal information if required to do so by law. 
  13. We can use the information we collect to enforce the [Terms of Service](http://chandlerproject.org/tos) and to keep the servers healthy. 
  14. We can still hang on to your info if we change names or business structures. 
  15. Your privacy is in part based on your ability to keep your data and account secure. 
  16. We don't want any information from people under 18. 
  17. People outside the US should expect to be bound by US privacy laws. 
  18. We may update the Privacy Policy as needed so please check back here periodically. 

* * *

##  Privacy Policy 

##  Last updated on August 29, 2007 

The Open Source Applications Foundation (“ _OSAF_ ”) believes that your privacy is very important. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of information we collect, how we use it, and the steps we take to keep your private information private. Our aim is to help you make an educated decision when choosing to use our Web sites and services and when you share information with us. 

###  What This Privacy Policy Covers 

This Privacy Policy pertains to the use of the Chandler Hub service and other OSAF services (the “ _Services_ ”), and the OSAF Web site at [www.osafoundation.org](http://ww.osafoundation.org/), and other OSAF Web sites (the “ _Web Sites_ ”). 

This Privacy Policy covers how OSAF treats information that OSAF collects and receives from its users. 

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is subject to the Chandler Hub Terms of Use. Your use of the Web Sites, the Services and any information you provide on the Web Sites is subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use. 

###  What this Privacy Policy Doesn’t Cover 

This Privacy Policy applies only to Web Sites and services that are owned and operated by OSAF. We do not exercise control over the sites linked to or from within our various services. These other sites may place their own [cookies](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#cookies) or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit information from you. We encourage you to read their privacy policies before you enter into an exchange with them. 

OSAF may allow other companies to serve advertisements on the Web Sites. These third-party advertisers use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on the Web Sites. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content to a certain audience. 

###  The Information We Collect and How We Use It 

Some aspects of the Services do not require you to register for an account or provide any [personal information](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#personalinfo). We can provide these services just by placing a cookie on your browser and associating your preferences with that [cookie](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#cookies). Read more about cookies below. 

For these no-registration-required services OSAF collects the following information: 

**Cookies** : A [cookie](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#cookies) is a small identifier containing a unique string of characters that is sent from the OSAF servers and saved by your browser software. Using the cookie approach provides maximum privacy protection while also allowing OSAF to provide the desired personalized services. Browsers are typically set to accept cookies, however, you can change the settings on your browser to notify you when a site is sending a cookie to your browser or, alternatively, to refuse cookies altogether. If your cookies are disabled, these no-registration-required OSAF services will not function properly. If the OSAF cookie is cleaned from your browser, and you haven’t registered with personally identifiable information, then all your preferences will be lost, and you will need to reset your preferences to continue using OSAF’s personalized services. 

**Log information** : When you use OSAF services, our servers automatically record the data that your browser sends whenever you visit a Web site. These [server logs](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#serverlogs) include data such as browser type, Internet Protocol address, your web request, the date and time of your requests, and your OSAF cookie(s) that uniquely identify your browser. 

**Clear GIFs information** : When you use the Web Sites, we may employ clear gifs (a.k.a. web beacons), which are used to anonymously track the online usage patterns of users without collecting any personally identifiable information about you. 

Clear GIFs, log information and cookies are [non-personal information](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#nonpersonalinfo) because such information is not collected or used in such a way that an individual user can be identified, for example, by name or email address. 

We use non-personal information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your current or subsequent visits to the Web Sites; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors and traffic; (e) diagnose or fix technology problems; (f) access your information after you sign in; and (h) market the Web Sites to advertisers and other third parties. 

For OSAF services where registration is required, we will collect the non-personal information described above, and in addition, we collect the following types of personal information for the following purposes (personal information is information that personally identifies you, such as your name, email address, home address, phone numbers, or other data which can be reasonably linked to such information): 

**Information you provide** : When you sign up for an OSAF service that requires registration, we ask you for [personal information](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#personalinfo). Examples of that information include your name, email address, birth date, account password, etc. 

**Collaborating with Colleagues** : When you provide your colleagues with the special URLs we provide to you in order for them to have “read only” or “read and write” privileges with respect to the information you have posted to the Chandler Hub service, we collect and store log information regarding such colleagues’ access to the service. 

**User communications** : If you send email to OSAF, we may retain those communications in order to reply to your inquiries, fulfill your requests and to improve our services. 

**Affiliated sites** : Some of OSAF’s services are provided in cooperation with other online services and Web sites. [Personal information](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#personalinfo) that you provide to those sites may be sent to OSAF in order to deliver the service to you on the OSAF site. This Privacy Policy also governs how we process such information. The affiliated sites may have different privacy practices and we suggest you also read their privacy policies. 

**Links** : OSAF may present links in a format that lets us keep track of when these links are clicked. We use this information to improve the quality of our services, to estimate traffic we send to third party sites, and to customize our content and advertising. 

Sensitive Information: We will not collect or use [sensitive information](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#sensitiveinfo) unless we obtain your prior consent. 

###  When We May Share Your Information 

OSAF shares [collected information](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#collectedinfo) (both [personal](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#personalinfo) and [non-personal](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#nonpersonalinfo) information) with our subsidiaries, affiliated companies or other trusted businesses or persons who process such information on our behalf in order for us to provide or improve our services. We require that these parties agree to process such information in compliance with this Privacy Policy, and to take reasonable confidentiality and security measures with respect to such information. 

We share non-personal information (such as anonymous Web site use data) with third-parties to assist them in understanding our Web Sites, including usage of our Web Sites and the services we provide and the success of advertisements and promotions. 

We may release collected information if required to do so by law, or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with state and federal laws (such as U.S. Copyright Law) or to respond to a court order, subpoena, or search warrant. It may be necessary to share collected information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities, including but not limited to, fraud, potential threats to public safety or the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use, or as otherwise permitted by law. 

We also reserve the right to disclose collected information that we believe is appropriate or necessary to enforce our Terms of Use, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend OSAF against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, to protect the security or integrity of our Web Sites, and to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of OSAF, our users or others. 

In the event that OSAF is acquired by or merged with a third party entity, we reserve the right to transfer or assign the information we have collected from you as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. If OSAF is involved in such a transaction we will notify you before your personal information becomes subject to a different privacy policy. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, we may not be able to control how your personal information is treated, transferred, or used. 

Except as described above, OSAF will not share your personal information with third parties unless you have elected to “opt in” to such sharing of your information. 

Please contact us for any additional questions about the management or use of personal data. 

###  Your Choices 

When you sign up for an OSAF service that requires registration we ask you for [personal information](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#personalinfo). If we want to use your personal information for purposes other than those described in this Policy, we will provide you with an effective way to opt into such use. 

We will not collect or use personal information for reasons other than those described in this Privacy Policy, unless we obtain your prior consent. 

You can decline to submit personal information to any of our services, in which case OSAF may not be able to provide those services to you. 

###  Information security 

We have adopted certain measures to preserve the integrity and security of your [personal information](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#personalinfo). We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any personal information and you provide such information at your own risk. 

###  Updating personal information 

For many of our services, we provide secure and easily accessible mechanisms for updating and correcting your [personal information](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#personalinfo) and preferences. For more information, please see the [FAQ](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/FAQ) pages. 

###  Our Commitment To Children's Privacy 

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, OSAF does not knowingly collect [personal information](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#personalinfo) on its Web Sites from persons under 18 years of age, and no part of our Web Sites are directed to persons under 18. If you are under 18 years of age, then please do not use or access the Web Sites at any time or in any manner. 

###  International Users 

The Web Sites are hosted in the United States and is intended for and directed to Users in the United States. If you are accessing the Web Sites from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use and disclosure that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of the Web Sites, which is governed by U.S. law, this Privacy Policy, and our Terms of Use, you are transferring your [personal information](http://chandlerproject.org/Projects/HubPrivacyPolicy#personalinfo) to the United States and you consent to that transfer. 

###  Changes to this Policy 

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will post those changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a prominent notice. Please revisit this page to stay aware of any material changes. Your continued use of the Web Sites or the Services constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any future revisions. 

###  More information 

For more information about our privacy practices, or for questions and complaints, please [email us](mailto::privacy@osafoundation.YOU-MUST-REMOVE-THIS-BEFORE-SENDING.org) any time, or write to us here: 

    OSAF Privacy
    c/o OSAF
    privacy@osafoundation.org
    543 Howard St. 5th Floor
    San Francisco, CA 94105 (USA)

##  OSAF Privacy Policy definitions and Faq 

###  What is personal information?

We consider "personal information" to be information you provide to us that personally identifies you, such as your name, email address, home address, phone numbers, or other data which can be reasonably linked to such information. 

###  What is non-personal information?

We define “non-personal information" as data we collect from many people and aggregate into groups so that it is no longer connected to individually identifiable users. 

###  What is collected information?

We define “collected information" as both the personal and non-personal information that we collect from our users. 

###  What is sensitive information?

We define "sensitive information" as personal information related to confidential medical information, racial or ethnic origins, political or religious beliefs or sexuality. 

###  What is an OSAF Account? 

In order for you to use some OSAF services, we need to be able to authenticate you and protect your preferences and personal information from unauthorized access. To do that, we ask that you sign up for a unique account, typically secured by your unique email address, a password and your name. Several services on OSAF may share this personal information in order to customize experiences and improve our services for you. No account information is shared with anyone other than OSAF except as specified in the Privacy Policy or with your consent. 

You can edit or terminate your account at any time through your OSAF Account settings. 

###  What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small file containing a unique string of characters that is sent from a Web site’s servers and saved by your browser software when you first visit the Web site. On subsequent visits to the same Web site, the cookie allows the site to recognize your browser. The unique string of characters in a cookie may store user preferences and other information. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is being sent. However, some Web site features or services may not function properly without cookies. 

###  What are server logs?

We maintain a set of computers called "servers" which are configured to provide web sites, pages, images, and other files to people who request them from those servers. These servers automatically record, or “log,” the page requests made when a user visits a Web site. These “server logs” include data such as browser type, Internet Protocol address, your web request, the date and time of your requests, and your cookie(s) that uniquely identify your browser. 

###  What information does OSAF receive if I click on a link displayed on OSAF? 

When you click on a link displayed on OSAF, we record the fact that someone using your browser, as identified by your unique cookie, clicked on that link. 

###  What protections do I have against government investigations into my use of OSAF services? 

OSAF complies with the same laws and processes that all lawful companies abide by, including search warrants, court orders, subpoenas and other processes seeking personal information. The primary protections you have against intrusions by the government are the laws that apply to where you live. 

If you have any additional questions or concerns about this Policy, please [email us](mailto:privacy@osafoundation.YOU-MUST-REMOVE-THIS-BEFORE-SENDING.org), or write us at: 

    OSAF Privacy
    c/o OSAF
    privacy@osafoundation.org
    543 Howard St. 5th Floor
    San Francisco, CA 94105 (USA)
